Guide to the Catalogue Department, Yale University Library, Records
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
Catalogue Department, Yale University Library, records
1900-2014
RU 303
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
70.25
(75 boxes)
The records consist of filing notes, cataloging manuals and guides, classification schemes, administrative files, and memoranda of the Catalog Department (previously spelled Catalogue Department). Topics include the Yale classification system, shelf lists, cataloging procedures, and filing courses at the Yale University Library.
Yale University. Library
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 32-C (YRG 32-C), Records of Yale University Library departments and offices.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is partially restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of filing notes, cataloging manuals and guides, classification schemes, administrative files, and memoranda of the Catalog Department (previously spelled Catalogue Department). Topics include the Yale classification system, shelf lists, cataloging procedures, and filing courses at the Yale University Library.
Academic libraries; Cataloging; Technical services (Libraries); Yale University. Library
- Records, circa 1932, 1940-1959; Accession 19ND-A-112
  - Manuscript Cataloguing Procedure 4 copies, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 1-4)
  - Filing courses, circa 1940s-50s (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Library of Congress. Card Division. List of Series of Publications for which Cards are in Stock. 4th edition. Annotated. (2 copies), 1932 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Records, circa 1930-1969; Accession 1988-A-042
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2055
  - Cutter, Charles A. Explanation of the Alphabetic-Order Marks, 1930 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - English Manuscripts in Yale University Library (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Index to classifications of Yale Memorabilia Collection, circa 1940s (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Library of Congress Depository Catalogue and utilization of Bibliographical Data produced by the Library of Congress in Cataloguing at the Yale University Library, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Manuscripts cataloguing procedure, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Manuscript cataloguing procedure: revisions, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Short Title Catalogue of books printed in Britain 1701-1800, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Yale University Author Subject Headings - 2 copies, circa 1943 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Guide to the YUL Classification Schedules with references to Library of Congress classes, 1987; Accession 1988-A-104
  The materials are open for research.
  - Guide to the YUL Classification Schedules with references to Library of Congress classes, 1987 (Box 1)
- Catalog department manuals, 1951-1987; Accession 1997-A-020 (Box 1)
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2032
- Old Yale classification schedules, and not on shelf inventories, circa 1900-1979; Accession 1997-A-037
  - Classification schedules, circa 1930
    - A - Bg59, circa 1930 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Bh - BB038.56, circa 1930 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - B041 - Bw93, circa 1930 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Bxl - CC73, circa 1930 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Cbl - Cj79, circa 1930 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - CI- Gr25 (Gs - Gx8 in box 14), circa 1930 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Hea - Hf48, circa 1930 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - Hf50 -Hfr, circa 1930 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - Hfs - Jc, circa 1930 (Box 9)
    - Je2 - Qoy, circa 1930 (Box 10)
    - R - Sb19, circa 1930 (Box 11)
    - Sb21 - Skpl, circa 1930 (Box 12)
    - S1- Syz, circa 1930 (Box 13)
    - Szl - 2n70, Music, 1899 - 1902, circa 1930 (Box 14)
    - Z23 - 253, 2 index (2 books), circa 1930 (Box 15)
  - Catalog books
    - 1.11-15, circa 1900 (Box 16)
    - 21.11 -29a611, circa 1900 (Box 17)
    - 30.11 - 32a.611, circa 1900 (Box 18)
    - 40 - 57.04, circa 1900 (Box 19)
    - 57a.19 - 74.56, circa 1900 (Box 20)
  - Books not on shelf inventory, 1930 September
    - A-N (Box 21)
    - N(Hymnology) - Zn ("W" and "Y" missing) (Box 22)
  - Corrections (Box 22)
  - Books Not on Shelf inventory (miscellaneous letters of the alphabet), circa 1939-1966
    - 1939 - 1950 (Box 23)
    - 1973 - 1979 (Box 24)
  - Memorandum, 1966 (Box 24)
- Administrative records of Catalog Dept.; classification books, pamphlets, schemes, and lists of classified material, 1910-1995; Accession 1997-A-058
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2031
  - R.L.I.N. rates and maintenance charges, 1983-1984 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Catalogue department reference material, Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Cataloguing cost, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Catalogue use, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Cataloguing output, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Catalogue department, organization, 1969-1985 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Cataloguing assistant, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Card processing division, 1971-1981 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Budget proposals, 1967-1982 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Catalog cards, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Book contins, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Bibliography department, 1980-1982 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Bibliographic center, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library, 1969-1988 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Beinecke library, 1979-1988 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Backlog, 1969-1976 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Automation project, 1972-1974 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Authority control, 1978-1982 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - African studies, 1982-1984 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Arabic cataloguing and classification, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Arabic, transliteration, 1957 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Archive tape, 1976-1983 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Archives, 1980-1981 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Microfilm dissertations, 1981-1982 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Music library, 1980-1982 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Name authority (NACO), 1986 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Meeting, May 16, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Near East cataloger, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - PCPP, 1969-1971 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Personnel department, 1971-1983 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Procedures, 1979-1982 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Vacations, 1972-1973 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Working conditions, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Yale bibliographic system, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Yale Medical Library, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Yale Health Plan, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Incunabula, 1946-1947 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Telephones and directories, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Thai, 1968-1970 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Title added entries, policy, 1982-1983 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - TIAA, CREF, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Travel, 1982-1986 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Save file, RLIN, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Searching division, 1969-1973 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Security, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - serials division, 1971-1982 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Shared cataloguing, 1973-1984 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Sick leave, 1971-1973 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Slavic and East European languages division, 1970-1973 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Staff meetings, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Stamping, 1976-1977 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Statistics, 1976-1983 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Statistics, subcommittee, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Storage, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Student assistants, 1968-1985 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Subject cataloguing division, 1959-1974 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Subject headings, 1962-1975 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Systems office, 1974-1975 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Technical services, 1966-1973 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Nuremberg trials, 1950 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Conservation library, 1951-1955 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Definitions, Yale staff, 1933-1935 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Departmental libraries, committee on subject representation, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Documents, 1944-1950 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Documents, municipal, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - East European accessions lost, 1954-1961 (Box 1, Folder 66)
  - Education library, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 67)
  - Griswold's library, 1956 (Box 1, Folder 68)
  - Industrial administration library, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 69)
  - Kiphuth library, 1954-1955 (Box 1, Folder 70)
  - Latin America, Bingham bibliography, 1935, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 71)
  - League of nations, 1930-1955 (Box 1, Folder 72)
  - Interfiling with official LC depository, 1951-1952 (Box 1, Folder 73)
  - LC, Southern Asia Acc list, 1955-1960 (Box 1, Folder 74)
  - LC, subject code, 1956-1958 (Box 1, Folder 75)
  - Lyman Beecher lectures, Undated (Box 1, Folder 76)
  - Microcards, June 2, 1951 (Box 1, Folder 77)
  - Migne patrologia, 1937-1944 (Box 1, Folder 78)
  - National Union Catalog (LC), including filming project, 1943-1953 (Box 1, Folder 79)
  - Reorganization, 1974-1983 (Box 1, Folder 80)
  - RLIN, ACQ, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 81)
  - Catalogue department, job descriptions, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 82)
  - Yale University Library, chart of accounts, revised fall 1986 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Yale University, chart of accounts, revised fall 1986 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - R.L.I.N. meeting minutes, 1978-1979 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - R.L.I.N. invoices, 1980-1982 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Cataloging statistics and annual reports (1 through 8), 1993-1995 (Box 2, Folder 5-12)
  - Catalogue department orientation program, 1989 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Statistics, 1989-1990 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Workstation, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Workstation, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Space planning, O.C.L.C., 1993 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Space planning, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Slavic stats, 1993-1995 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Serials recon, 1994-1995 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - R.L.I.N. searches, 1993-1995 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - R.L.I.N. accounts, 1984-1989 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Performance evaluation, team leaders, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Processing Services department, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Performance evaluation, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Performance planning, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Performance expectations, 1992-1994 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Hebrew Recon, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - O.C.L.C., 1994 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Latin America Recon, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Computer files, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 31)
  - Subject ledger, Undated (Box 2, Folder 32)
  - Church bodies, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 33)
  - Author headings (personal) (corporate) except for church bodies, 1941-1942 (Box 2, Folder 34)
  - Church bodies (healings) A.L.A., 1938 (Box 2, Folder 35)
  - Methodist church headings, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 36)
  - Missions, classification, 1940-1943 (Box 2, Folder 37)
  - Divinity School, Law School, areas of responsibility, 1947-1948 (Box 2, Folder 38)
  - Dioceses, 1950 (Box 2, Folder 39)
  - Thomas Aquinas, Albertus Magnus, classifications, 1949 (Box 2, Folder 40)
  - Orthodox Eastern Church, Russian, 1948 (Box 2, Folder 41)
  - Pamphlets, report on classing of pamphlets, 1947 (Box 2, Folder 42)
  - Foreign institutions, Undated (Box 2, Folder 43)
  - Ledger, Undated (Box 3)
  - Ledger, Undated (Box 4)
  - Annual report (including individual quarterly statistics), 1965-1966 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Annual report 1966-1967, including individual quarterly statistics (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Catalogue department reports 1967-1968 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Annual report 1984-1985 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Annual report 1985-1986 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Annual report 1969-1970 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Annual report 1970-1971 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Annual report 1971-1972 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Annual report 1972-1973 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Catalogue department annual report 1960-1961 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Catalogue department annual report 1958-1959 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Catalogue department annual report 1959-1960 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Catalogue department annual report 1957-1958 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Catalogue department annual report 1956-1957 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Catalogue department annual report 1955-1956 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Annual report 1954-1955 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Catalogue department annual report 1954-1955 (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Catalogue department annual report, 1952-1953 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Catalogue department annual report 1953-1954 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Catalogue department annual report, 1951-1952 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Annual report 1950-1951 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Catalogue department annual report 1949-1950 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Catalogue department annual report 1948-1949 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Annual report 1947-1948 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Catalogue department annual report, 1946-1947 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Catalogue department annual report 1945-1946 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Annual report 1943-1944 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Catalogue department annual report 1944-1945 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Annual report 1942-1943 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Annual report 1941-1942 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Annual report 1940-1941 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Catalogue department annual report 1939-1940 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Annual report 1938-1939 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Annual report 1937-1938 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Annual report 1936-1937 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Annual report 1935-1936 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Annual report 1934-1935 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Annual report 1933-1934 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Catalogue department annual report 1930-1931, 1932-1933, 1930-1933 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Annual report 1926-1927, 1929-1930, 1926-1930 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Cataloguers, exchange of 1949-1951 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Catalogue department annual report 1923-1924, 1925-1926, 1923-1926 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Catalogue department report 1905-1915, 1922-1923, 1905-1923 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - Annual report 1975-1976 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - Annual report 1976-1977 (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Annual report 1977-1978 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Annual report 1978-1979 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Annual report 1979-1980 (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Annual report 1986-1987 (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Annual report 1970-1971 (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Annual report 1987-1988 (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - Annual report 1972-1973 (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - Annual report 1973-1974 (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - Annual report 1974-1975 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Annual report 1985-1986 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Annual report 1984-1985 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Annual report 1981-1982 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Annual report 1983-1984 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Annual report 1982-1983 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Annual report 1988-1989 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Annual report 1987-1988 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Annual report 1971-1972 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Annual report 1981-1982 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Annual report 1980-1981 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Classification, religion, 1951 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Annual report 1950-1978 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Staffing, output, economy, 1974 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Brief outline of the organization of the Yale University library in relation to the catalogue department, 1944-1945 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Survey of member library cataloging policy and practice, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Machine-Aided Technical Processing System, Manual of Procedures, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Filing lessons, official and public catalogues, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Typing manual, card processing division, 1973 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - cataloging of serials, third edition, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Descriptive cataloguing manual, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Catalog department manual, 1944 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - Annual report 1980-1981 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Annual report, 1979-1980 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Marking of call numbers on volumes, boxes, etc..., 1951 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Annual report, 1985-1986 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Yale University Library, 1965-1974 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - United Nations, 1950 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Urdu, Panjabi, and Pushto, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Welsh books, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Xerox, 1956-1963 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Xerox copyflo, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Y.C.A.L., 1966-1967 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Collections, German Literature, YCGL, 1931-1951 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Yale geographical table, Undated (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Yale University, 1971-1973 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Subject headings, subdivisions, serials, 1946-1951 (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Subjects, assignment, decisions, etc..., 1953 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Tibetan cataloging, 1950-1954 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Title added entries, 1950-1956 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Trade catalogs, 1937 (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Transportation, 1939-1945 (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Turkish books, 1952-1956 (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - Turkish (Shepard), 1963 (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Typewriters, keyboard, Undated (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - Tables of geographical divisions, 1952-1953 (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - Subject, subdivisions, 1946-1951 (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - Subject experiment, report, 1957 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Subject experiment, 1952-1956 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Subject headings, 1942-1958 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Subject headings, date divisions, 1952 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Subject headings, folklore, 1940 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Subject headings, subdivided by locality, 1945-1950 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Subject division meetings, 1949-1958 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Rare book team, 1988-1994 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Anonymous biography, 1944-1945 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Adaptations, memo and notes, 1949-1950 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - African newspapers, 1964 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - (The) United Church Board for World Ministries, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - American tracts, 1963 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Analyzing, 1952 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Analyzing cooperative, L.C., 1964 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Area study programs, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Automation, papers and charts relative to, 1966 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Braille, 1937-1941 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Barrie collection, Beinecke, 1958 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Beinecke library bound collections of pamphlets, 1948-1960 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Beinecke library, catalogs, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Beinecke, Clark collection of books on horses, 1964 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Beinecke library, uncatalogued special collections, 1957-1963 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Binding department, Undated (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Bi-Physics, 1955-1959 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - British tracts, 1930-1948 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - British tracts, sermons, etc..., 1953 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Burmese cataloging, LC for Yale, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Classification, Undated (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Ledger, Undated (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - Classification, class D, universal and old world history, 1916 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Classification, class B, B-BJ, philosophy, 1950 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Classification, class V, naval science, 1910 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Yale Law library classification, 1939 (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Classification, class T, technology, 1937 (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Classification, class E-F, 1913 (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - Classification, literature, 1915 (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Classification, literature, 1915 (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - Classification, geography, Undated (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - Classification of the library of Union Theological Seminary, 1957 (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Ledger, Undated (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Classification, class B, part II, religion, 1927 (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Education (general), Undated (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Classification, class Q, science, 1950 (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Oxford and Cambridge classification, 1935 (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Philosophy and psychology, K classification, Undated (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Classification, class C, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Zoology, Undated (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Subject subdivisions for individual colleges, Undated (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Classification schedule for the college libraries of Yale University, Undated (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Classification of the library of Union Theological Seminary in New York City, 1957 (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Classification, outline scheme of classes, 1926 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Foreign office names, 1921 (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Classification, Revolutionary and Napoleonic wars, Undated (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Classification, Literature, 1915 (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Classification, class Z, Bibliography and Library Science, 1926 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Classification, Literature, 1915 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Classification schedules, Continental Europe, Undated (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Outline of classification and discussion, Undated (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Classification, Latin American, Undated (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Missionary countries, Latin America, Asia, Africa, and Oceanica, 1948-1949 (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - E classification schedule, Undated (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Geology, Zoology, and Natural History, Undated (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Classification of the library of Union Theological Seminary in the city of New York, 1939 (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Classification, war, 1919-1939 (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Latin America, 1942 (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Classification, European war, 1914-1918 (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Classification, I, Undated (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Political theory, Undated (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Russian Philology, Undated (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Classification, class J, Political Science, 1924 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Classification, I, Circa 1941 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Classification, I, Undated (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Index to F classification, Oriental Languages, Literature, and tables, Undated (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Explanation of the alphabetic order marks, Undated (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Classification schedule, class P, Law, Undated (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - L.C. classification, class N, Fine Arts, 1922 (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Oxford and Cambridge classification, 1935 (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Developments toward modern cataloging practice at Harvard and Yale, 1935 (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Outline of classification, Undated (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Classification, E, Undated (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Catalog department manual, 1944-1946 (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Method of counting the Yale library, 1930-1931 (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Classification, class X, Bibliography and Library Science, 1915 (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Classification, B, Undated (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Periodicals, Learned Societies, Indexes, Undated (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Subject bibliography, X, Undated (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Classification schedule for shorthand, Undated (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Classification schemes for small libraries, Undated (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Abstracts, 1930-1940 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Classification, religion, 1952 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Selective book retirement program, manual of procedures, 1964 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Classification, class B, religion, 1927 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - European war, 1939-1945 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Classification, Military Science, 1910 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Classification, Music, Undated (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Classification, Bp-Bz, Undated (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Asia and the Far East, Undated (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Classification, class S, 1928 (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - Classification, class P, modern languages, celtic languages, Undated (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Classification, class C, Auxiliary Sciences of History, 1915 (Box 9, Folder 32)
  - Classification, class P, PJ-PM, 1935 (Box 9, Folder 33)
  - Index to the classification of A, B, C, Q, R, S, Undated (Box 10)
  - Subject manual, British Art, 1974 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Classification, class H, Social Science, 1950 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Catalogue de la Biblioteque Dramatique, Undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - General rules, developing book numbers in new classification, Undated (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Untitled, Undated (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Country, city tables, Undated (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Outline of the classification and location of books in the Yale library, 1957 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Classification B, special topics, Undated (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Classification, C and E, Latin American, Undated (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Oriental languages and literatures, Undated (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Classics index, Undated (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Classification schedule, K, Philosophy, 1949 (Box 11, Folder 12)